<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://wayneye.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://wayneye.me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-09-11T18:11:45-07:00</updated><id>https://wayneye.me/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wayne’s Geek Life</title><subtitle>I am a software engineer, technical lead and also a geek, I&apos;ve immersed in software/web development for 14 years, I hack using these languages: Python, Golang, JavaScript/nodejs, Ruby/RoR, C#. I am an AWS Certified Solutions Architect (2017-2019), PMP and CodeProject MVP.</subtitle><author><name>Wayne Ye</name></author><entry><title type="html">BMW Convertible As My Beater Car</title><link href="https://wayneye.me/BMW-Convertible-As-My-Beater-Car" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BMW Convertible As My Beater Car" /><published>2020-06-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://wayneye.me/BMW-Convertible-As-My-Beater-Car</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wayneye.me/BMW-Convertible-As-My-Beater-Car">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Life is too short to drive boring cars&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;third&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/Life_s_Too_Short_to_Drive_Boring_Cars.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/Life_s_Too_Short_to_Drive_Boring_Cars.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/cW-8o_rfh8s&quot;&gt;bought a 2015 BMW X5&lt;/a&gt; Dec last year, it has been half a year so far (with 2 months she stayed inside the garage for most of the time due to the pandemic), I am pretty satisfied with it, her condition is absolutely excellent, everything works, yes you see it correctly, after 5 years of its life, there was nothing broken, as BMW vehicle built in recent years, this is something not VERY easy.  My plan is to keep it as long as possible before it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.motor1.com/reviews/406108/bmw-maintenance-cost/&quot;&gt;turns into an endless money pit&lt;/a&gt;, and keeping her value as high as possible, one of the major reason I bought her was its AWD and comfortable so that I can drive it to Lake Tahoe often during winter season, for other seasons I was seriously thinking about buying a beater car, to put my mileage on it instead of this pricey Bimmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-requirements&quot;&gt;My requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve considers are listed &amp;amp; ranked below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Must be a stick shift&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Must be a convertible (I rented a few times but never owned one)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Must have two rows of seats&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Below $5k (unless outstanding condition)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Must look very cool to me&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Color is NOT one of: &lt;span style=&quot;color: red&quot;&gt;red&lt;/span&gt; (sir, pull me over, aren’t you see I am shining and I am driving aggressively?), &lt;span style=&quot;color: dark green&quot;&gt;dark green&lt;/span&gt; (especially &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.miata.net/gallery/images/91brg.jpg&quot;&gt;late 1990s green&lt;/a&gt;, on gosh, I couldn’t tolerate it), &lt;span style=&quot;color: black&quot;&gt;black&lt;/span&gt; (I like sunshine and I keep extreme hot all around the year, and I work even hotter for convertibles ^_^, yes since I am in bay area).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Gas saver&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Reliability is mandatory, I didn’t mention it because majority of the case, an old manual transmission car is much more reliable than an auto one).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My ideal candidates were: Toyota Celica, BMW E46, Ford Mustang, Nissan 350Z, Mercedes Benz CLK and SLK (yes since it looks gorgeous to me and if it is a manual I can compromise on #3 above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait!! Mazda Miata??  I am really sorry I have so many friends who are Miata lovers, but due to #3 above, I didn’t look for it(in the future for sure).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-met-with-love&quot;&gt;We met with love&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 3+ months of patient (hours after hours) market search, I bought this beautiful 2001 BMW 330CI on May 28 2020:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;third&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/330CI-1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/330CI-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/330CI-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/330CI-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/330CI-3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/330CI-3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;third&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/stick-shift.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/stick-shift.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/330CI-4.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/330CI-4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/330CI-Spec.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/330CI-Spec.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It got 166,6xx miles on it, and I paid $3800, plus $15 DMV title transfer fee.  Her body style was originally designed by DesignWorksUSA back to 1990s and she still looks &lt;strong&gt;gorgeous and very stylish&lt;/strong&gt; to me, believe it or not, even after 19 years!  Especially compare with modern BMW models:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/BWM-kidney-future.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/BWM-kidney-future.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…:rofl:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This legendary bimmer is equipped with a naturally aspirated inline six &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BMW_M54&quot;&gt;M54 engine&lt;/a&gt; (which many people believe it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://bimmerlife.com/2018/10/19/the-5-best-bmw-engines-post-1990/&quot;&gt;one of the best engine BMW ever made&lt;/a&gt;), it produces a very respectful 225HP, 214 ft-lbs. @ 3500 rpm, 0-60 miles takes less than 7 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The condition of this car is really decent, all the major components should work are working: engine/manual transmission runs strong, all the fluid are well maintained, tires/breaks have some life left, painting is shining, the rest nice to have features were broken: convertible top sometimes failed (I had to operate manually), cruise control not work at all, passenger side turn light was broken, and driver side turn light got dropped and flied few days ago while I was “flying” on highway 101^_^  Battery T bolt was missing as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I ordered the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/amz-orders.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/amz-orders.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I’ve driven it for about 100 miles so far about 1 week, I can simply describe my experience as: &lt;strong&gt;a stick shift, a steering wheel and a smiling face&lt;/strong&gt;:smiley:.  Compare with my X5, due to 330CI’s lighter weight, lower gravity point, I admit: it is much more fun of driving this 330CI convertible!  And since it is my beater, my plan is to drive it for at least another 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;side-story-with-2020-740i&quot;&gt;Side story with 2020 740i&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A side interesting story, the convertible top was broken after only two days, so I made an appt at BMW of Mountain View and had them inspected it.  They charged me $256 for manually closing it, and estimated $500-600 parts + 10 hours of labor = $3200 for fixing the top, no doubt, I even didn’t bother negotiating…
However, since it was weekend and they were pretty short of mechanics, so while I parked my car there, they said they can provide me a loaner car, I asked without thinking: “well, please give me M2 Competition”, the loaner car manager said: “sorry sir, you got the right choice but we don’t have it at the moment”, he recommended me this 2020 740i, it is too luxury… With &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bmw.com/en/innovation/the-main-driver-assistance-systems.html&quot;&gt;BMW driving assistance&lt;/a&gt; (similar with Tesla’s auto pilot), I probably would never buy a luxury car like this:sweat_smile:  Unless there is a right person who encourages me to buy one:wink:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;third&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/740i-1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/740i-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/740i-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/740i-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/740i-drive.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2020-06-03-BMW-As-My-Beater-Car/740i-drive.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drive-through-golden-gate-bridge&quot;&gt;Drive through Golden Gate Bridge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!-- Courtesy of embedresponsively.com //--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;responsive-video-container&quot;&gt;

  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/jmuyIp6CgMo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;driving-my-beater-330ci-with-my-buddy---teddy&quot;&gt;Driving my beater 330CI With my buddy - Teddy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!-- Courtesy of embedresponsively.com //--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;responsive-video-container&quot;&gt;

  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/u2MdmPj0tQs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Wayne Ye</name></author><category term="Life" /><category term="Car" /><category term="Life" /><summary type="html">Life is too short to drive boring cars I bought a 2015 BMW X5 Dec last year, it has been half a year so far (with 2 months she stayed inside the garage for most of the time due to the pandemic), I am pretty satisfied with it, her condition is absolutely excellent, everything works, yes you see it correctly, after 5 years of its life, there was nothing broken, as BMW vehicle built in recent years, this is something not VERY easy. My plan is to keep it as long as possible before it turns into an endless money pit, and keeping her value as high as possible, one of the major reason I bought her was its AWD and comfortable so that I can drive it to Lake Tahoe often during winter season, for other seasons I was seriously thinking about buying a beater car, to put my mileage on it instead of this pricey Bimmer. My requirements I’ve considers are listed &amp;amp; ranked below: Must be a stick shift Must be a convertible (I rented a few times but never owned one) Must have two rows of seats Below $5k (unless outstanding condition) Must look very cool to me Color is NOT one of: red (sir, pull me over, aren’t you see I am shining and I am driving aggressively?), dark green (especially late 1990s green, on gosh, I couldn’t tolerate it), black (I like sunshine and I keep extreme hot all around the year, and I work even hotter for convertibles ^_^, yes since I am in bay area). Gas saver (Reliability is mandatory, I didn’t mention it because majority of the case, an old manual transmission car is much more reliable than an auto one). My ideal candidates were: Toyota Celica, BMW E46, Ford Mustang, Nissan 350Z, Mercedes Benz CLK and SLK (yes since it looks gorgeous to me and if it is a manual I can compromise on #3 above) Wait!! Mazda Miata?? I am really sorry I have so many friends who are Miata lovers, but due to #3 above, I didn’t look for it(in the future for sure). We met with love After 3+ months of patient (hours after hours) market search, I bought this beautiful 2001 BMW 330CI on May 28 2020: It got 166,6xx miles on it, and I paid $3800, plus $15 DMV title transfer fee. Her body style was originally designed by DesignWorksUSA back to 1990s and she still looks gorgeous and very stylish to me, believe it or not, even after 19 years! Especially compare with modern BMW models: …:rofl: This legendary bimmer is equipped with a naturally aspirated inline six M54 engine (which many people believe it was one of the best engine BMW ever made), it produces a very respectful 225HP, 214 ft-lbs. @ 3500 rpm, 0-60 miles takes less than 7 seconds. The condition of this car is really decent, all the major components should work are working: engine/manual transmission runs strong, all the fluid are well maintained, tires/breaks have some life left, painting is shining, the rest nice to have features were broken: convertible top sometimes failed (I had to operate manually), cruise control not work at all, passenger side turn light was broken, and driver side turn light got dropped and flied few days ago while I was “flying” on highway 101^_^ Battery T bolt was missing as well. So I ordered the following: So far I’ve driven it for about 100 miles so far about 1 week, I can simply describe my experience as: a stick shift, a steering wheel and a smiling face:smiley:. Compare with my X5, due to 330CI’s lighter weight, lower gravity point, I admit: it is much more fun of driving this 330CI convertible! And since it is my beater, my plan is to drive it for at least another 5 years. Side story with 2020 740i A side interesting story, the convertible top was broken after only two days, so I made an appt at BMW of Mountain View and had them inspected it. They charged me $256 for manually closing it, and estimated $500-600 parts + 10 hours of labor = $3200 for fixing the top, no doubt, I even didn’t bother negotiating… However, since it was weekend and they were pretty short of mechanics, so while I parked my car there, they said they can provide me a loaner car, I asked without thinking: “well, please give me M2 Competition”, the loaner car manager said: “sorry sir, you got the right choice but we don’t have it at the moment”, he recommended me this 2020 740i, it is too luxury… With BMW driving assistance (similar with Tesla’s auto pilot), I probably would never buy a luxury car like this:sweat_smile: Unless there is a right person who encourages me to buy one:wink: Drive through Golden Gate Bridge Driving my beater 330CI With my buddy - Teddy</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AWS reinvent 2019 - Las Vegas</title><link href="https://wayneye.me/AWS-reinvent-Las-Vegas" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AWS reinvent 2019 - Las Vegas" /><published>2019-12-07T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-12-07T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://wayneye.me/AWS-reinvent-Las-Vegas</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wayneye.me/AWS-reinvent-Las-Vegas">&lt;p&gt;This is my second time attending AWS re-Invent, last time was year 2017, the purpose of this blog is to summarize what I’ve learned, impressed and entertained :smile:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-12-07-AWS-reinvent-Las-Vegas/at-reinvent-logo.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-12-07-AWS-reinvent-Las-Vegas/at-reinvent-logo.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;At reinvent logo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-12-07-AWS-reinvent-Las-Vegas/crazy-crowd-at-midnight-madness.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-12-07-AWS-reinvent-Las-Vegas/crazy-crowd-at-midnight-madness.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Crazy crowd at midnight madness party&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall during my week staying my daily schedule was listening to sessions mixed with slack/emails during the daylight, and party/social in the evening time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the keynotes/sessions have been uploaded here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://reinvent.awsevents.com/learn/keynotes/&quot;&gt; https://reinvent.awsevents.com/learn/keynotes/ &lt;/a&gt; and all announcements were summarized &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/?sc_channel=em&amp;amp;sc_campaign=re:Invent%20Recaps%202019&amp;amp;sc_medium=em_212626&amp;amp;sc_content=launch_t1launch_reinvent&amp;amp;sc_geo=mult&amp;amp;sc_country=global&amp;amp;sc_outcome=launch&amp;amp;trk=em_212626&amp;amp;mkt_tok=eyJpIjoiTXpnME4ySTBOREZtWkRFMyIsInQiOiJHU0J5UndVeHBhZFJvc1g5SG5EYzhYeGpkNjhCUldkTXpwXC91TlExc1BPTDhBdmlyMCsyVjVwZmZmOHVuUFVqNTduSTR2Y1hreHpoQW9jMDJWaXUxeCtGbFNxSW5IZmRoUUs1U3RaQVwvdjA1U0x4RVJJQU9TZFZNSDFuS0VnVFFUdmRWMXVHSnFVakpWamRwcmRieFpxQT09In0%3D#Explore_Announcements&quot;&gt;at this page&lt;/a&gt;, my personal top 5 thrilled announcements are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/braket/&quot;&gt;Braket&lt;/a&gt;: Quantum computing is seriously coming!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/deepcomposer&quot;&gt;Deep Composor&lt;/a&gt;: machine learning (and AI) is already mainstream technology, AWS will never wanna be out of this game, so they announced this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07YGZ4V5B&quot;&gt;a machine learning-enabled musical keyboard for developers&lt;/a&gt;, would that be a game changer?  Let’s see!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/cdk/&quot;&gt;AWS CDK&lt;/a&gt;: no doubt I will try it out and &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; possible I will be favoring it over terraform/CloudFormation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/builders-library&quot;&gt;Amazon Builders’ Library&lt;/a&gt;: Amazon’s official best practices, white papers on arhcitecting/developing on the AWS Cloud Platform.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/outposts&quot;&gt;Outposts&lt;/a&gt;: won’t have any impact for developers, DevOps engineers or architects who work on AWS at daily basis, but could expand AWS business to even broader regions/countries, pretty ambitious!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the session videos have been uploaded to: https://reinventvideos.com/, well done and very necessary, too!  &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/industries/aws-reinvent-2019-telco-industry-guide/&quot;&gt;With more than 60,000 attendees this year&lt;/a&gt; I am pretty sure not even one attendee was able to listen to all the sessions and have to made some trade offs, so this is our go to place to watch the ones we had missed or even overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My focus areas are: general architecting, best practices, security, Serverless, containers, databases and chaos engineering practices, list below are the sessions I watched:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N_3IaOVcIO0&quot;&gt;Best practices for Amazon S3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vbyjpMeYitA&quot;&gt;AWS re:Invent 2019: Performing chaos engineering in a serverless world (CMY301)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9As_ZIjUGmY&quot;&gt;Deep dive into AWS Cloud Development Kit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M-Fh0OzliJI&quot;&gt;Running Kubernetes at Amazon scale using Amazon EKS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2WG01wJIGSQ&quot;&gt;What’s New in Amazon Aurora&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time I was also very proud to stay in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://reinvent.awsevents.com/learn/certifications/&quot;&gt;AWS Certification Lounge&lt;/a&gt; again (I watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZOIkOnW640A&quot;&gt;Andy’s keynotes&lt;/a&gt; at this lounge) and I collected a pretty great group of certified swags as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-12-07-AWS-reinvent-Las-Vegas/AWS-certicied-swags.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-12-07-AWS-reinvent-Las-Vegas/AWS-certicied-swags.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;AWS Certified Swags&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also attended the AWS Certification Appreciation Reception at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brooklynbowl.com/las-vegas&quot;&gt;Brooklyn Bowl Las Vegas&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-12-07-AWS-reinvent-Las-Vegas/certified-appreciatian-party-1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-12-07-AWS-reinvent-Las-Vegas/certified-appreciatian-party-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-12-07-AWS-reinvent-Las-Vegas/certified-appreciatian-party-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-12-07-AWS-reinvent-Las-Vegas/certified-appreciatian-party-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;AWS Certification Appreciation Reception&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the event on Saturday, I spent my time in doing something “meaningful and exciting”: &lt;a href=&quot;/2019-12-07-SkyJump-Las-Vegas&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SkyJump from Stratosphere Tower at Las Vegas - Smile all the way down&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written on the plane from LAS-&amp;gt;SFO
Dec 7th 2019&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Wayne Ye</name></author><category term="IT-Industry" /><category term="IT-Industry" /><category term="AWS" /><summary type="html">This is my second time attending AWS re-Invent, last time was year 2017, the purpose of this blog is to summarize what I’ve learned, impressed and entertained :smile: At reinvent logo Crazy crowd at midnight madness party Overall during my week staying my daily schedule was listening to sessions mixed with slack/emails during the daylight, and party/social in the evening time. All the keynotes/sessions have been uploaded here: https://reinvent.awsevents.com/learn/keynotes/ and all announcements were summarized at this page, my personal top 5 thrilled announcements are: Braket: Quantum computing is seriously coming! Deep Composor: machine learning (and AI) is already mainstream technology, AWS will never wanna be out of this game, so they announced this a machine learning-enabled musical keyboard for developers, would that be a game changer? Let’s see! The AWS CDK: no doubt I will try it out and very possible I will be favoring it over terraform/CloudFormation. Amazon Builders’ Library: Amazon’s official best practices, white papers on arhcitecting/developing on the AWS Cloud Platform. Outposts: won’t have any impact for developers, DevOps engineers or architects who work on AWS at daily basis, but could expand AWS business to even broader regions/countries, pretty ambitious! All the session videos have been uploaded to: https://reinventvideos.com/, well done and very necessary, too! With more than 60,000 attendees this year I am pretty sure not even one attendee was able to listen to all the sessions and have to made some trade offs, so this is our go to place to watch the ones we had missed or even overlooked. My focus areas are: general architecting, best practices, security, Serverless, containers, databases and chaos engineering practices, list below are the sessions I watched: Best practices for Amazon S3 AWS re:Invent 2019: Performing chaos engineering in a serverless world (CMY301) Deep dive into AWS Cloud Development Kit Running Kubernetes at Amazon scale using Amazon EKS What’s New in Amazon Aurora This time I was also very proud to stay in the AWS Certification Lounge again (I watched Andy’s keynotes at this lounge) and I collected a pretty great group of certified swags as well: AWS Certified Swags I also attended the AWS Certification Appreciation Reception at Brooklyn Bowl Las Vegas: AWS Certification Appreciation Reception After the event on Saturday, I spent my time in doing something “meaningful and exciting”: SkyJump from Stratosphere Tower at Las Vegas - Smile all the way down</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SkyJump from Stratosphere Tower at Las Vegas - Smile all the way down</title><link href="https://wayneye.me/2019-12-07-SkyJump-Las-Vegas" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SkyJump from Stratosphere Tower at Las Vegas - Smile all the way down" /><published>2019-12-07T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-12-07T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://wayneye.me/SkyJump-Las-Vegas</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wayneye.me/2019-12-07-SkyJump-Las-Vegas">&lt;p&gt;Instead of spending any cent in the money pit casinos, I’d chose to do something more meaningful and exciting :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;third&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-12-07-SkyJump-Las-Vegas/SkyJump-1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-12-07-SkyJump-Las-Vegas/SkyJump-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-12-07-SkyJump-Las-Vegas/SkyJump-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-12-07-SkyJump-Las-Vegas/SkyJump-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-12-07-SkyJump-Las-Vegas/SkyJump-3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-12-07-SkyJump-Las-Vegas/SkyJump-3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;SkyJump Las Vegas&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;SkyJump Las Vegas holds the Guinness World Record for highest commercial decelerator descent with an official height of 829 ft (253 m) and is located at Stratosphere Las Vegas. As part of its grand opening event, Las Vegas Mayor Oscar Goodman presented a written proclamation deeming April 20, 2010 as SkyJump Day in Las Vegas.
  – Wikipedia (https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SkyJump_Las_Vegas)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;!-- Courtesy of embedresponsively.com //--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;responsive-video-container&quot;&gt;

  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Q1987wC9ODA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Wayne Ye</name></author><category term="Life" /><category term="Life" /><category term="Travel" /><summary type="html">Instead of spending any cent in the money pit casinos, I’d chose to do something more meaningful and exciting :) SkyJump Las Vegas SkyJump Las Vegas holds the Guinness World Record for highest commercial decelerator descent with an official height of 829 ft (253 m) and is located at Stratosphere Las Vegas. As part of its grand opening event, Las Vegas Mayor Oscar Goodman presented a written proclamation deeming April 20, 2010 as SkyJump Day in Las Vegas. – Wikipedia (https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SkyJump_Las_Vegas)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ireland Trip 2019</title><link href="https://wayneye.me/Ireland-Trip-2019" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ireland Trip 2019" /><published>2019-06-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://wayneye.me/Ireland-Trip</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wayneye.me/Ireland-Trip-2019">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;WHEN YOU ARE OLD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you are old and grey and full of sleep, &lt;br /&gt;
And nodding by the fire, take down this book, &lt;br /&gt;
And slowly read, and dream of the soft look &lt;br /&gt;
Your eyes had once, and of their shadows deep; &lt;br /&gt;
How many loved your moments of glad grace, &lt;br /&gt;
And loved your beauty with love false or true, &lt;br /&gt;
But one man loved the pilgrim soul in you, &lt;br /&gt;
And loved the sorrows of your changing face; &lt;br /&gt;
And bending down beside the glowing bars, &lt;br /&gt;
Murmur, a little sadly, how Love fled &lt;br /&gt;
And paced upon the mountains overhead &lt;br /&gt;
And hid his face amid a crowd of stars. 
– By &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poets/william-butler-yeats&quot;&gt;William Butler Yeats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;当你年老时 
　　 　　傅浩译 &lt;br /&gt;
当你年老，鬓斑，睡意昏沉， &lt;br /&gt;
在炉旁打盹时，取下这本书， &lt;br /&gt;
慢慢诵读，梦忆从前你双眸， &lt;br /&gt;
神色柔和，眼波中倒影深深； &lt;br /&gt;
多少人爱你风韵妩媚的时光， &lt;br /&gt;
爱你的美丽出自假意或真情， &lt;br /&gt;
但唯有一人爱你灵魂的至诚， &lt;br /&gt;
爱你渐衰的脸上愁苦的风霜； &lt;br /&gt;
弯下身子，在炽红的壁炉边， &lt;br /&gt;
忧伤地低诉，爱神如何逃走， &lt;br /&gt;
在头顶上的群山巅漫步闲游， &lt;br /&gt;
把他的面孔隐没在繁星中间。 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;邀您一起，与我一同品味爱尔兰，上帝所眷恋的绿宝石岛。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;机缘巧合的旅行&quot;&gt;机缘巧合的旅行&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;由于公司的&lt;a href=&quot;https://wayneye.com/gallery/adsk-worldcup-2019&quot;&gt;2019年足球世界杯在都柏林举办&lt;/a&gt;，我因此有幸首次到欧洲旅行，本来是想说在都柏林打完比赛玩1天，然后去伦敦转2天就回上海跟家人团聚，结果没有想到&lt;a href=&quot;Apply-UK-Visit-VISA&quot;&gt;等了3周日落帝国都不给我签证&lt;/a&gt;，因此我决定花2天好好探索下绿宝石岛。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;地理气候历史和文化&quot;&gt;地理，气候，历史和文化&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;爱尔兰地处大不列颠岛的西面，如果不算英吉利海峡，可以算是欧亚大陆的最西段，可谓是天涯海角，好些年前在网上闲逛时还记得爱尔兰本地人自嘲雨水多，制作了下面的图片：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/ireland-wet-floor.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/ireland-wet-floor.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;在这次旅途中跟本地人交谈确认过了，他们说大概超过70%的天会下雨，我大胆揣测下，也许整座岛全部晴天的日头一年不会超过30天吧:)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;历史上爱尔兰由于邻近大英帝国，可没少受欺负，尽管同属一国，但自私的英国政客并不将爱尔兰的凯尔特人一视同仁，我印象比较深刻的就是使爱尔兰人口减少四分之一的&lt;a href=&quot;https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E7%88%B1%E5%B0%94%E5%85%B0%E5%A4%A7%E9%A5%A5%E8%8D%92&quot;&gt;爱尔兰大饥荒&lt;/a&gt;，我了解的这些历史以及之前提到的签证经历，使我在出发前心理上天然就非常偏向爱尔兰。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;爱尔兰首都都柏林有文学之都的美誉，曾经产生过许多杰出的文学家，例如诺贝尔文学奖得主威廉·巴特勒·叶芝、蕭伯納还有James Joyce等等，几天旅程下来让我都或多或少沾染上了些文学气息。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;经济上根据IMF的统计，爱尔兰的&lt;a href=&quot;https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E5%90%84%E5%9B%BD%E4%BA%BA%E5%9D%87%E5%9B%BD%E5%86%85%E7%94%9F%E4%BA%A7%E6%80%BB%E5%80%BC%E5%88%97%E8%A1%A8_(%E5%9B%BD%E9%99%85%E6%B1%87%E7%8E%87)&quot;&gt;人均GDP高居全球第四&lt;/a&gt;，引用一段维基百科的描述：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;都柏林是20世纪末和21世纪初爱尔兰经济增长奇迹的中心点，这一时期爱尔兰经济经常保持两位数的增长，被称为凯尔特之虎的年代。该市的生活水准已经有了戏剧性的增长，同时生活费用也已经暴涨。2008年，都柏林名列世界最富裕城市的第5位。根据一份资料，都柏林现在名列全球最昂贵城市的第16名（在欧洲名列第8，不包括俄罗斯城市）。它还被列为世界上生活开支第3高的城市。不过，它也是全世界工资水平第2高的城市，超过纽约市和伦敦，仅次于苏黎世。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;旅程&quot;&gt;旅程&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在都柏林踢完比赛后，晚上我订好了车，发现一个非常有趣的情况，也许是国情不一样，在爱尔兰租车自动挡出奇的贵，如下图Economy的AT竟然比Intermidiate的MT要贵：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Avis-Car-rental.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Avis-Car-rental.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;坦白说，我6年没有开手动挡了，此次是首次来爱尔兰，而且要靠左行哦，也就意味着跟以前右手换挡不一样，我得左手换挡，虽说13年我在新加坡时开过几次自动挡（坡县是靠左行），但是考虑到上述因素，依然还是极有挑战，不过嘛，I am always brave! 事实上，我敢打赌即便我看到MT和AT的价格一样，我依然还是会选手动:smile:。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;周日早上的早餐是酒店自助，即使昨天打了大半天比赛，体能消耗巨大，我却仍然非常克制地只盛了如下的一点东西：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Sunday-Breakfast.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Sunday-Breakfast.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;香肠和鸡蛋补充蛋白质，豆类，面包补充淀粉和碳水补充碳水，蔬果补充维生素，豆浆补充损失的钙质，所以呢，饮食才真是暴露年龄呢，不过放心，本君心理年龄是很难超过20的啦。。。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;吃完早餐check out后我就直接跟同事们一块打车去机场，给了辆Nissan逍客(Qashqai)，长这样：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Avis-Nissan-Qashqai.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Avis-Nissan-Qashqai.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;内部忘了拍照了，网上找了张图贴下面:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Nissan-Qashqai-Interior.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Nissan-Qashqai-Interior.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;发现了吧？手动6档，对我来讲又是首次，10年前我开的思域是手动5档的, 无所谓了，多换换更健康:) 其实大概10分钟就完全习惯了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我很快就离开了都柏林市区，来到西南部的爱尔兰第二大城市Cork，这里曾被Lonely Planet评选为世界前十位旅游城市之一，顺便提下我的行程安排主要是自然景观，虽然我对于人文，历史和城市景观也很有兴致，但是时间有限（我只有1天半）只能有所取舍。我来到English Market，本来打算在这里解决午餐，结果不知其周日关门歇业：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/English-Market.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/English-Market.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;没关系，我也不太饿，然后这里犯了一个木有经验的错误，我在Downtown找了个车库停好车后就下出来瞎转悠，然而还没过10分钟就开始下大雨了，好家伙，6月份的爱尔兰一下雨气温骤降，我成了街上唯一一位穿短袖T桖的人，只得躲进商城里等雨停，白白浪费了半个多小时:disappointed_relieved:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;随手拍了几张照片就赶路了：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Cork-McDonald.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Cork-McDonald.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;科克市中心的麦当劳&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Cork-Part.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Cork-Part.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;科克市的普通民宅&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Countryside.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Countryside.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;离科克不远的乡村小镇&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;一路下雨，而且路越来越窄，心里只能祈祷到我心心念的下个景点，请别下雨了吧:pray: 路上无聊拍了段视频：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Courtesy of embedresponsively.com //--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;responsive-video-container&quot;&gt;

  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/KXpzr2Yt-5M&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;开了大概2个多小时，终于到了心心念的景点：&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ring_of_Kerry&quot;&gt;凯里之环(Ring of Kerry)&lt;/a&gt;，&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Ring-Of-Kerry.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Ring-Of-Kerry.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Wild-Atlantic-Way.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Wild-Atlantic-Way.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;凯里之环和狂野大西洋之路的路牌&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;凯里之环是一条全长近180公里的游览自驾路线，本身也是狂野大西洋之路的一部分，沿途风光绝妙。既有海滨滩涂，还有海岸峭壁；既有森林山野，还有草坪牧场；既可以远观群山起伏，也可以近赏田园风光。星球大战-最后的绝地武士在这里取景（http://www.kerryexperiencetours.ie/ring-of-kerry/star-wars-the-last-jedi-in-kerry/）。 非常感恩，雨停了，由于美景是在太多太震撼，我基本上是开开停停（大概二三十次吧），无需赘言，请欣赏照片：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-Gorgeous-View.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-Gorgeous-View.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-Mountain.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-Mountain.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-Campsite.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-Campsite.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-Sea-View.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-Sea-View.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-Farms.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-Farms.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-Creek.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-Creek.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-Me-At-Beach.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-Me-At-Beach.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-Houses.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-Houses.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-Mountain-View.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-Mountain-View.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;因为时间关系，我规划的路线是从Kenmare一路往西开，到Sneem到Waterville，经过大半个凯里之环后北面的Tralee住一晚民宿，大概5点多钟在Kenmare的一家礼品店跟店家询问得知晚上10点半才天黑，那么预估我的时间非常充足，看下面的地图只要不花费过多时间晚上大概8点多我应该可以到Tralee的民宿：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/map-of-kerry.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/map-of-kerry.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7点多钟在这家&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Quinlan+%26+Cooke+Boutique+Hotel+%26+QC%E2%80%99s+Seafood+Restaurant/@51.9459349,-10.2271513,10.51z/data=!4m12!1m6!3m5!1s0x484ff31dab3d706f:0xe4638f1804f04710!2sQuinlan+%26+Cooke+Boutique+Hotel+%26+QC%E2%80%99s+Seafood+Restaurant!8m2!3d51.9458617!4d-10.2270294!3m4!1s0x484ff31dab3d706f:0xe4638f1804f04710!8m2!3d51.9458617!4d-10.2270294&quot;&gt;QC’s Seafood Restaurant&lt;/a&gt;解决了晚餐：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-QC.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-QC.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;到了&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com.sg/rooms/28183787?source_impression_id=p3_1561254329_DZECSdTqK%2B74cmwJ&quot;&gt;Ms. Margrate的家&lt;/a&gt;大概快9点了，跟她聊了下得知她是心理康复的护士（非常严重的心理疾病比如有过犯罪记录的病人），兼职做Airbnb大概几年时间，聊了十几分钟，我清理了下东西，发现钱包里集齐了世界三大货币：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/three-main-currencies.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/three-main-currencies.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我看着窗外的天色，已经9点半了居然还没有天黑（我潜意识里以为呢，9点多总要日落了吧，这里并没有到北欧的纬度啊，事后查了下，爱尔兰北纬50多度，实际上我此前去过最北的地方哈尔滨也只有北纬45度，超过66度就有极昼了），查了下今日落日时间是10点03分，我就请教她附近有没有很美的追日落的地方，她推荐了Blennerville Windmill，开车7分钟，极有激情的我便立马驱车出发，然而小有遗憾（其实也不遗憾，因为这天气算正常了，要知道三分之二的天都下雨呢:smile:），由于云层太厚，并没有机会看到明显的晚霞，也就只拍到了下面2张照片：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Tralee-Blennerville-Windmill.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Tralee-Blennerville-Windmill.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Tralee-Blennerville-Windmill-Flags.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Tralee-Blennerville-Windmill-Flags.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;此次来到爱尔兰，一大目标就是住在当地人的民宿，跟淳朴的爱尔兰人交流，体验下本地人的生活，这个小目标算是实现了，请看房子外观和我温馨的小床：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-house-external.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-house.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-house-external.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/RoK-house-external.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms. Margret给了我个好评:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Review-By-Margret.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Review-By-Margret.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;第二天早上起床，一路沿海岸线向北，两边的景色依然是田园风：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure style=&quot;width:1200px&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Countryside-view.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Countryside-view.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Countryside-view-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Countryside-view-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;沿途经过The Woollen Market100欧买了件纯羊毛衫：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/The-Woollen-Market.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/The-Woollen-Market.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;大概上午11点多钟，抵达了此次行程本君最期待的地方：莫赫悬崖（The Cliffs of Moher），他是欧洲最高的悬崖，最高点高出大西洋海平面有214米，极其雄伟壮阔，展现大西洋之狂野的最佳之处！诸多电影在这里取景，包括《哈利·波特与混血王子》，请看下面的片段：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Courtesy of embedresponsively.com //--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;responsive-video-container&quot;&gt;

  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/B0mVNFCcMXQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;先给您上几张我拍的：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoM-landscape.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoM-landscape.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoM-landscape-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoM-landscape-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoF-3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoF-3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoF-4.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoF-4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoF-5.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoF-5.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;再给您欣赏3幅驴友们拍的:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1500456759136-362ab38eec6d?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=2250&amp;amp;q=80&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1500456759136-362ab38eec6d?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=2250&amp;amp;q=80&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;From unsplash&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1459381484519-d5191fddc858?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=2251&amp;amp;q=80&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1459381484519-d5191fddc858?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=2251&amp;amp;q=80&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;From unsplash&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/100629421@N07/24475077681/in/photolist-DhMaTX-Lh3Ujz-q18Kg3-W3JMep-WXTopN-qxjydU-c1H4nd-2bQw9cb-MUtLBN-6aNyFn-bvCLET-MUuwTy-88H3Av-p5aVpv-8frEAd-dqwC8r-nJ7So9-oaoM9e-7dit5b-bWGfrd-7x91uC-7b57YD-5kxKeo-dvKqHL-bQWh5r-kBHoN6-Dog5to-28Y7PU3-6khmtr-57YrtA-28DXNRZ-apSDRj-2cDvsbQ-oqqt7-VCHDgy-69Eee5-ni2gLF-pK5mBN-2a2Ys38-X1ZxsB-9oFYKp-2a31dW4-Lh42rF-34FiaX-rDS72S-aLwHve-oky7c5-k9jcQG-ag2nr3-8oBbHG&quot; title=&quot;Sunset On The Cliffs Of Moher&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/1662/24475077681_1fd8bbc818_k.jpg&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot;1365&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset On The Cliffs Of Moher&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Safety-advice.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Safety-advice.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Memorial.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Memorial.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;随处可见的安全提示以及一座纪念碑, RIP&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;显然本君不算很乖的游客^_^：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;third&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoM-Danger-0.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoM-Danger-0.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoM-Danger-1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoM-Danger-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoM-Danger-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoM-Danger-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;third&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoM-Danger-3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoM-Danger-3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoM-Danger-4.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoM-Danger-4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoM-Danger-5.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoM-Danger-5.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;不过呢，当然也有人比我疯狂得多的，比如这位老兄：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Super-Danger.jpg&quot;&gt;
  
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Super-Danger.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
      

    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我听到边上有人惊叹：“This is the most silly thing I’ve ever seen…”，这位老兄脚下确实是百米悬崖，而且他还激情四射地高举国旗，要知道这里的风力可能会超过7级，我上面那些作妖的照片有一个实际上下面还有凸出的岩石，只是我专门给帮我拍照的朋友们交代了“构图要点”:blush:，所以看起来有点骇人而已，比如您看这张：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  
  &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoM-no-Danger.jpg&quot;&gt;
  
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/CoM-no-Danger.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
      

    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway，表学我就对了。。。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;驾车返回都柏林后入住了又一间民宅Hazelwood：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Hazelwood-Bedroom.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Hazelwood-Bedroom.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;房东Mrs.Ann非常友好而且很有经验，她的大house有6间卧室，我跟她以及她可爱的小孙女聊了几句：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/With-Ann.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/With-Ann.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;临走时拍了张照留念，逍客和Hazelwood大house：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Park-At-Hazelwood.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Park-At-Hazelwood.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mrs.Ann精心摆好的餐具（早餐自助）：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Hazelwood-Breakfast-table.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Hazelwood-Breakfast-table.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Tax-return.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-20-Ireland-Trip/Tax-return.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;在机场临走时退税&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;装备&quot;&gt;装备&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以上所有照片都是用我的华为Mate 20X拍摄，有些自拍是用的一只华为自拍杆+脚架，坦白说吧，我实在是太懒了，也没有足够的慧根去做照片后期，好在华为浴霸四摄像头非常优秀，足以填补镜头后面那个头的不足:smile:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;总结&quot;&gt;总结&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;写下这篇游记只是希望留下美好记忆，平时确实比较忙，没太多时间码字，如果您能够耐着心看到这里，希望能带给您些许欢乐，使您有了旅游和探索的兴趣，欢迎留言，谢谢！&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S.一个人研究攻略，制定行程有些boring，希望下次能&amp;gt;=2个人。&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Wayne Ye</name></author><category term="Life" /><category term="Life" /><category term="Travel" /><summary type="html">WHEN YOU ARE OLD When you are old and grey and full of sleep, And nodding by the fire, take down this book, And slowly read, and dream of the soft look Your eyes had once, and of their shadows deep; How many loved your moments of glad grace, And loved your beauty with love false or true, But one man loved the pilgrim soul in you, And loved the sorrows of your changing face; And bending down beside the glowing bars, Murmur, a little sadly, how Love fled And paced upon the mountains overhead And hid his face amid a crowd of stars. – By William Butler Yeats 当你年老时 　　 　　傅浩译 当你年老，鬓斑，睡意昏沉， 在炉旁打盹时，取下这本书， 慢慢诵读，梦忆从前你双眸， 神色柔和，眼波中倒影深深； 多少人爱你风韵妩媚的时光， 爱你的美丽出自假意或真情， 但唯有一人爱你灵魂的至诚， 爱你渐衰的脸上愁苦的风霜； 弯下身子，在炽红的壁炉边， 忧伤地低诉，爱神如何逃走， 在头顶上的群山巅漫步闲游， 把他的面孔隐没在繁星中间。 邀您一起，与我一同品味爱尔兰，上帝所眷恋的绿宝石岛。 机缘巧合的旅行 由于公司的2019年足球世界杯在都柏林举办，我因此有幸首次到欧洲旅行，本来是想说在都柏林打完比赛玩1天，然后去伦敦转2天就回上海跟家人团聚，结果没有想到等了3周日落帝国都不给我签证，因此我决定花2天好好探索下绿宝石岛。 地理，气候，历史和文化 爱尔兰地处大不列颠岛的西面，如果不算英吉利海峡，可以算是欧亚大陆的最西段，可谓是天涯海角，好些年前在网上闲逛时还记得爱尔兰本地人自嘲雨水多，制作了下面的图片： 在这次旅途中跟本地人交谈确认过了，他们说大概超过70%的天会下雨，我大胆揣测下，也许整座岛全部晴天的日头一年不会超过30天吧:) 历史上爱尔兰由于邻近大英帝国，可没少受欺负，尽管同属一国，但自私的英国政客并不将爱尔兰的凯尔特人一视同仁，我印象比较深刻的就是使爱尔兰人口减少四分之一的爱尔兰大饥荒，我了解的这些历史以及之前提到的签证经历，使我在出发前心理上天然就非常偏向爱尔兰。 爱尔兰首都都柏林有文学之都的美誉，曾经产生过许多杰出的文学家，例如诺贝尔文学奖得主威廉·巴特勒·叶芝、蕭伯納还有James Joyce等等，几天旅程下来让我都或多或少沾染上了些文学气息。 经济上根据IMF的统计，爱尔兰的人均GDP高居全球第四，引用一段维基百科的描述： 都柏林是20世纪末和21世纪初爱尔兰经济增长奇迹的中心点，这一时期爱尔兰经济经常保持两位数的增长，被称为凯尔特之虎的年代。该市的生活水准已经有了戏剧性的增长，同时生活费用也已经暴涨。2008年，都柏林名列世界最富裕城市的第5位。根据一份资料，都柏林现在名列全球最昂贵城市的第16名（在欧洲名列第8，不包括俄罗斯城市）。它还被列为世界上生活开支第3高的城市。不过，它也是全世界工资水平第2高的城市，超过纽约市和伦敦，仅次于苏黎世。 旅程 在都柏林踢完比赛后，晚上我订好了车，发现一个非常有趣的情况，也许是国情不一样，在爱尔兰租车自动挡出奇的贵，如下图Economy的AT竟然比Intermidiate的MT要贵： 坦白说，我6年没有开手动挡了，此次是首次来爱尔兰，而且要靠左行哦，也就意味着跟以前右手换挡不一样，我得左手换挡，虽说13年我在新加坡时开过几次自动挡（坡县是靠左行），但是考虑到上述因素，依然还是极有挑战，不过嘛，I am always brave! 事实上，我敢打赌即便我看到MT和AT的价格一样，我依然还是会选手动:smile:。 周日早上的早餐是酒店自助，即使昨天打了大半天比赛，体能消耗巨大，我却仍然非常克制地只盛了如下的一点东西： 香肠和鸡蛋补充蛋白质，豆类，面包补充淀粉和碳水补充碳水，蔬果补充维生素，豆浆补充损失的钙质，所以呢，饮食才真是暴露年龄呢，不过放心，本君心理年龄是很难超过20的啦。。。 吃完早餐check out后我就直接跟同事们一块打车去机场，给了辆Nissan逍客(Qashqai)，长这样： 内部忘了拍照了，网上找了张图贴下面: 发现了吧？手动6档，对我来讲又是首次，10年前我开的思域是手动5档的, 无所谓了，多换换更健康:) 其实大概10分钟就完全习惯了。 我很快就离开了都柏林市区，来到西南部的爱尔兰第二大城市Cork，这里曾被Lonely Planet评选为世界前十位旅游城市之一，顺便提下我的行程安排主要是自然景观，虽然我对于人文，历史和城市景观也很有兴致，但是时间有限（我只有1天半）只能有所取舍。我来到English Market，本来打算在这里解决午餐，结果不知其周日关门歇业： 没关系，我也不太饿，然后这里犯了一个木有经验的错误，我在Downtown找了个车库停好车后就下出来瞎转悠，然而还没过10分钟就开始下大雨了，好家伙，6月份的爱尔兰一下雨气温骤降，我成了街上唯一一位穿短袖T桖的人，只得躲进商城里等雨停，白白浪费了半个多小时:disappointed_relieved: 随手拍了几张照片就赶路了： 科克市中心的麦当劳 科克市的普通民宅 离科克不远的乡村小镇 一路下雨，而且路越来越窄，心里只能祈祷到我心心念的下个景点，请别下雨了吧:pray: 路上无聊拍了段视频： 开了大概2个多小时，终于到了心心念的景点：凯里之环(Ring of Kerry)， 凯里之环和狂野大西洋之路的路牌 凯里之环是一条全长近180公里的游览自驾路线，本身也是狂野大西洋之路的一部分，沿途风光绝妙。既有海滨滩涂，还有海岸峭壁；既有森林山野，还有草坪牧场；既可以远观群山起伏，也可以近赏田园风光。星球大战-最后的绝地武士在这里取景（http://www.kerryexperiencetours.ie/ring-of-kerry/star-wars-the-last-jedi-in-kerry/）。 非常感恩，雨停了，由于美景是在太多太震撼，我基本上是开开停停（大概二三十次吧），无需赘言，请欣赏照片： 因为时间关系，我规划的路线是从Kenmare一路往西开，到Sneem到Waterville，经过大半个凯里之环后北面的Tralee住一晚民宿，大概5点多钟在Kenmare的一家礼品店跟店家询问得知晚上10点半才天黑，那么预估我的时间非常充足，看下面的地图只要不花费过多时间晚上大概8点多我应该可以到Tralee的民宿： 7点多钟在这家QC’s Seafood Restaurant解决了晚餐： 到了Ms. Margrate的家大概快9点了，跟她聊了下得知她是心理康复的护士（非常严重的心理疾病比如有过犯罪记录的病人），兼职做Airbnb大概几年时间，聊了十几分钟，我清理了下东西，发现钱包里集齐了世界三大货币： 我看着窗外的天色，已经9点半了居然还没有天黑（我潜意识里以为呢，9点多总要日落了吧，这里并没有到北欧的纬度啊，事后查了下，爱尔兰北纬50多度，实际上我此前去过最北的地方哈尔滨也只有北纬45度，超过66度就有极昼了），查了下今日落日时间是10点03分，我就请教她附近有没有很美的追日落的地方，她推荐了Blennerville Windmill，开车7分钟，极有激情的我便立马驱车出发，然而小有遗憾（其实也不遗憾，因为这天气算正常了，要知道三分之二的天都下雨呢:smile:），由于云层太厚，并没有机会看到明显的晚霞，也就只拍到了下面2张照片： 此次来到爱尔兰，一大目标就是住在当地人的民宿，跟淳朴的爱尔兰人交流，体验下本地人的生活，这个小目标算是实现了，请看房子外观和我温馨的小床： Ms. Margret给了我个好评:) 第二天早上起床，一路沿海岸线向北，两边的景色依然是田园风： 沿途经过The Woollen Market100欧买了件纯羊毛衫： 大概上午11点多钟，抵达了此次行程本君最期待的地方：莫赫悬崖（The Cliffs of Moher），他是欧洲最高的悬崖，最高点高出大西洋海平面有214米，极其雄伟壮阔，展现大西洋之狂野的最佳之处！诸多电影在这里取景，包括《哈利·波特与混血王子》，请看下面的片段： 先给您上几张我拍的： 再给您欣赏3幅驴友们拍的: From unsplash From unsplash 随处可见的安全提示以及一座纪念碑, RIP 显然本君不算很乖的游客^_^： 不过呢，当然也有人比我疯狂得多的，比如这位老兄： 我听到边上有人惊叹：“This is the most silly thing I’ve ever seen…”，这位老兄脚下确实是百米悬崖，而且他还激情四射地高举国旗，要知道这里的风力可能会超过7级，我上面那些作妖的照片有一个实际上下面还有凸出的岩石，只是我专门给帮我拍照的朋友们交代了“构图要点”:blush:，所以看起来有点骇人而已，比如您看这张： Anyway，表学我就对了。。。 驾车返回都柏林后入住了又一间民宅Hazelwood： 房东Mrs.Ann非常友好而且很有经验，她的大house有6间卧室，我跟她以及她可爱的小孙女聊了几句： 临走时拍了张照留念，逍客和Hazelwood大house： Mrs.Ann精心摆好的餐具（早餐自助）： 在机场临走时退税 装备 以上所有照片都是用我的华为Mate 20X拍摄，有些自拍是用的一只华为自拍杆+脚架，坦白说吧，我实在是太懒了，也没有足够的慧根去做照片后期，好在华为浴霸四摄像头非常优秀，足以填补镜头后面那个头的不足:smile: 总结 写下这篇游记只是希望留下美好记忆，平时确实比较忙，没太多时间码字，如果您能够耐着心看到这里，希望能带给您些许欢乐，使您有了旅游和探索的兴趣，欢迎留言，谢谢！ P.S.一个人研究攻略，制定行程有些boring，希望下次能&amp;gt;=2个人。</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Apply UK Visit VISA</title><link href="https://wayneye.me/Apply-UK-Visit-VISA" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apply UK Visit VISA" /><published>2019-06-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://wayneye.me/Apply-UK-Visit-VISA</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wayneye.me/Apply-UK-Visit-VISA">&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was planning to attend #adskfootball2019 in Dublin, Ireland from Jun 14th to Jun 16th, 2019:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-06-06-Apply-UK-VISA/adsk-football-2019.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-06-06-Apply-UK-VISA/adsk-football-2019.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Autodesk Football Tournament 2019&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to attend, I needed applying Ireland VISA, and since I was planning to fly back to Shanghai later in June, so I thought I could just fly from SF to Dublin, then Dublin to Shanghai, and soon I realized that there is no direct flight from DUB to PVG, so a practical (and also very fun and economic) option is to fly from Dublin to London, and then London to Shanghai, bingo ^_^&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-visa-application-experience&quot;&gt;The VISA application experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most appropriate VISA for me would be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/transit-visa/visitor-in-transit-visa&quot;&gt;Visitor in Transit VISA&lt;/a&gt;, which means I must have in/out flights and must leave UK within 48 hours, sounds good, I can stay in London two days, two nights, and since it was just 1 month away, I thought applying this kind of VISA would be relatively faster and easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the first step is to make an appointment at USCIS and process 10 finger printings, short say: &lt;em&gt;10-printed&lt;/em&gt;, it was not that bad since the most close USCIS office is just 15 minutes of walking from Autodesk 1 Market office.  After doing this I got a receipt and instructions which guides me the next step: mail all the required documents to UK Consulate in New Your: a letter to explain the purpose of the visit, financial proof and all my family members’ profile, and most important: I must mail them my passport, inside this instruction it clearly instruct appliers to buy a shipping label from a VFS global: https://www.vfsglobal.co.uk/us/en/premium-services:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-06-06-Apply-UK-VISA/VFS-Premium.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-06-06-Apply-UK-VISA/VFS-Premium.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;VFS-Premium Services&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I won’t spend even 410 bucks to buy their “Premium Service”, there is a section in the bottom of the page “Most popular services”, and I chose “Round Trip Courier Service - up to 2lbs” which is 72 bucks (later on after I read some posts in Quora I realized this is not required, I can simply just purchase a return label from UPS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So since I have to mail my passport and I would also apply Ireland VISA, and I visited the Ireland consulate and talked to a really nice lady officer there, explained my situation and she told me it is ok, they will process my VISA application without holding my passport, I can go ahead mail my passport to UK consulate, I appreciated her considerate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mailed my passport on May 23rd, i.e. 20 days before the tournament, I truly hoped my application can be processed fast enough.  However, the fact was there was no progress after two weeks, on Jun 5th I couldn’t wait any longer, and I realized there isn’t an online portal to track the VISA status nor a phone number to call, I called the UK consulate in San Francisco and the stuff was really rude and kept emphasizing they are not responsible for any VISA service, and I was redirected to a robot audio saying I can visit their website for contacting method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some googling and struggling I found their contact methods at: https://www.gov.uk/contact-ukvi-inside-outside-uk/y/outside-the-uk/english&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Contact UK Visas and Immigration in English
  You can call or email English-speaking staff with a question about your application. Contact centre staff cannot give you advice about your personal circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;By phone
  Telephone: 00 44 203 481 1736
  Monday to Friday, 24 hours
  Calls cost £1.37 per minute on top of your standard network charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;By email
  Email UK Visas and Immigration. 
  Emails enquiries cost £5.48. You will not be charged for any follow-up emails about the same enquiry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You’ll get a reply to your email within 2 days, except on Saturdays, Sundays and UK public holidays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I called this number and the very first voice I heard was to enter my credit card information, and after 2 minutes of wait a human picked up the phone and stating immediately without even letting me to say hello: “before you talk please allow us to emphasize the disclaimer blah, blah…”, this last about 40 seconds, and I finally got chance to speak, after explaining my situation I begged: “&lt;strong&gt;please mail back me my passport immediately, I don’t need VISA any more, thank you!!&lt;/strong&gt;”.  I don’t want to recap these horrible moments, I ended up by calling them twice and got charged &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$1.75 * 2 + $15.68 + $29.68 = $48.86&lt;/code&gt; for a single purpose as I roared above^.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, don’t get me wrong, I fully respect UK, a great country that contributed a ton to humane being, I have several friends from UK as well.  However, IMHO, &lt;strong&gt;visitor who plan travel to a certain place because they are expecting a pleasant journey, they hope a wonderful trip so that it can be shared to their friends and relatives, also to create some unforgettable memory&lt;/strong&gt;, whereas after experiencing this unpleasant, not friendly, or let me say it directly: arrogant VISA processing process: 10-printed + super detailed forms + non-traceable progress + insanely expensive inquiry phone charge VISA experience, this could kill all of their positive passion.  For my case please remember: after all I was just applying a Visitor in Transit VISA which only allowing me to stay in this country for &lt;strong&gt;less than 48 hours&lt;/strong&gt;, but it almost destroyed my entire travel plan because of their “impressive efficiency”😠&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The total cost on me so far are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;VISA fee: $86&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;VFS global service fee: $75&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phone call: $48.86&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UPS shipping labels: $67.54&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Approximate 20+ raw hours input on this VISA application&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-06-06-Apply-UK-VISA/Anachronous_map_of_the_British_Empire.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-06-06-Apply-UK-VISA/Anachronous_map_of_the_British_Empire.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
      Prosperous period of UK Under the rule of Queen Victoria (1819-1901), origin: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_empire_on_which_the_sun_never_sets&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The empire on which the sun never sets&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-06-06-Apply-UK-VISA/EU-United_Kingdom.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-06-06-Apply-UK-VISA/EU-United_Kingdom.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        UK today (https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Kingdom)
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;updates&quot;&gt;Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jun 8th: until the time I wrote this post (Saturday Jun 8th), my passport is still on the way back to San Francisco.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jun 10th: received an email UKHubVISAInfo: “Your UK visa application has been dispatched from the UK Visa Section. –Croydon”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jun 11th: I finally received my passport at 11:45 AM, so the UK consulate in NYC didn’t issue me a VISA eventually, sure, fine!  Maybe they were just too busy with Brexit and really didn’t have time to process my 48 hours VISA during the past 3 weeks, I understand but I wrote a reply email to them below: &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2019-06-06-Apply-UK-VISA/VFS.png&quot; alt=&quot;Email reply to VFS&quot; title=&quot;Email reply to VFS&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jun 11th: I ran to the Ireland consulate immeditely and got to see Ms. Molly the 3rd time, as always, she is so kind, helpful and considerate, she pasted my approved short-stay travelling VISA within 1 minute and expressed her wishes to my upcoming trip in Ireland, I appreciated and told her I decided to stay in Ireland for two more days, I also asked her whether or not let me bring anything she needs from Ireland, she said no with smile and appreciation.  I will update on this later :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Wayne Ye</name></author><category term="Life" /><category term="Life" /><summary type="html">Background I was planning to attend #adskfootball2019 in Dublin, Ireland from Jun 14th to Jun 16th, 2019: Autodesk Football Tournament 2019 In order to attend, I needed applying Ireland VISA, and since I was planning to fly back to Shanghai later in June, so I thought I could just fly from SF to Dublin, then Dublin to Shanghai, and soon I realized that there is no direct flight from DUB to PVG, so a practical (and also very fun and economic) option is to fly from Dublin to London, and then London to Shanghai, bingo ^_^</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Master AWS Development Video Published</title><link href="https://wayneye.me/Master-AWS-Development-Video-Published" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Master AWS Development Video Published" /><published>2019-05-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-05-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://wayneye.me/Master-AWS-Development-Published</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wayneye.me/Master-AWS-Development-Video-Published">&lt;h2 id=&quot;course-overview-video&quot;&gt;Course overview video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yzZ7u5k7Q7M&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;publishing-information&quot;&gt;Publishing information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 8 months of continuously hard working, this &amp;lt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Master AWS Development&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;gt; video course is now live at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.packtpub.com/virtualization-and-cloud/mastering-aws-development-video&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Packt Website&lt;/a&gt;, I described this course as below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is the gold standard of the cloud. If you are web and cloud computing developer, your life becomes much easier by diving deeper into AWS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This course shows you how to use AWS services such as IAM, S3, EC2, and RDS/Dynamo to make your applications reliable and have a consistent performance. You’ll build modern serverless applications on the cloud, and use native computing solutions such as Lambda ECS/Fargate to implement cutting-edge container technology. Finally, learn a few popular AWS services like SQS, Cognito, and Kinesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;By the end of this course, you’ll be a master at building, deploying, and managing your applications on AWS. And you’ll know how to scale and secure your applications thanks to industry best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.packtpub.com/virtualization-and-cloud/mastering-aws-development-video&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img style=&quot;width: 500px;margin: 20px 0 0 20%;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-05-08-Master-AWS-Development-Published/v11847_low.png&quot; alt=&quot;Marstering AWS Development Video Course&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-motivation&quot;&gt;The motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In June 2018, PacktPub contacted me and asked my interest for recording a video course, they provided a few topics like AWS, Python, Docker, etc, I knew it could be very challenging but also pretty cool thing to do, so I accepted their invitation without hesitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-journey&quot;&gt;My journey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing begins easily, I actually struggled quite a few weeks on the audio quality.  My collaborator &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ranjita-panda-85737b12b/&quot;&gt;Ranjitap Panda&lt;/a&gt; suggested me to buy &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Blue-Snowball-Microphone-Brushed-Aluminum/dp/B002OO333Q/ref=sr_1_7?crid=MFDYMJ898LW7&amp;amp;keywords=blue+microphone&amp;amp;qid=1558027821&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sprefix=blue+micro%2Caps%2C197&amp;amp;sr=8-7&quot;&gt;this Microphone&lt;/a&gt;, I did and it was quite decent, however, my working room isn’t quite soundproof, so she suggested me to buy something like &lt;a href=&quot;https://express.google.com/u/0/product/14999533088633590141_483183884403381036_5916206?utm_source=google_shopping&amp;amp;utm_medium=tu_prop&amp;amp;utm_content=eid-lsjeuxoeqt&amp;amp;gtim=CPCPwdrs3baPKhD67br-_fi4isQBGPCz2hkiA1VTRCiQ-cHnBTCujOkC&amp;amp;utm_campaign=5916206&amp;amp;gclid=CjwKCAjwlPTmBRBoEiwAHqpvhR80piK0OZcxPrMsLaqS39LvCaCDl9RBX4S9SwsibW1LTSZKIm6B1hoCpr8QAvD_BwE&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; to improve the quality, well, I looked at it and I wasn’t that convinced by its effectiveness :sweat_smile:.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to DIY a super professional “recording studio”, it wasn’t so hard after 2 days of hand making:
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-05-08-Master-AWS-Development-Published/Studio-1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-05-08-Master-AWS-Development-Published/Studio-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-05-08-Master-AWS-Development-Published/Studio-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/2019-05-08-Master-AWS-Development-Published/Studio-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;DIYed super proffessional personal audio recording studio ^_^&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So just a moving box and a few pieces of &lt;a href=&quot;https://detail.tmall.com/item.htm?id=586105899658&amp;amp;ali_refid=a3_430620_1006:1196010016:N:z0OShXcL+rtIFJcT4Z2izQ==:a642190c156466fd7c802c60481c7916&amp;amp;ali_trackid=1_a642190c156466fd7c802c60481c7916&amp;amp;spm=a230r.1.14.3&amp;amp;skuId=415859080730&quot;&gt;this stuff from Taobao&lt;/a&gt;, pretty cool, isn’t it :smile:, but most important, it is &lt;strong&gt;free and fun&lt;/strong&gt;!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the initial back and force, I started recording video courses, and I soon realized this was much harder than I originally expected, usually I needed spending &lt;strong&gt;6-10 raw working hours&lt;/strong&gt; to prepare one video course, and then spent another half an hour to record it, I wasn’t too much concerned about my Chinglish accent (there are many videos courses recorded by Indian English, Japanese English, etc), my accent might be the worst but this shouldn’t stop me from trying :smile:  Those raw working hours was invested on the following aspects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video structure and outline (&amp;lt;10%)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Knowledge recap and investigate (10%)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Content of narration (%60-%80)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Environment and demo preparation (10%)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slides (&amp;lt;10%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The journey was really challenging, besides, I was having a true tough time during the second half of year 2018, this significantly impacted my outcome for this video course, I actually seriously thought about giving up, for quite several times, but eventually I managed and survived:sun_with_face:.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hitting year 2019, I was doing better, faster and I believe the quality of video was becoming better IMHO, eventually I completed all the video and submitted the assessment during early Apr, 2019, I felt thankful, and indeed, exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you very much for your valuable time in reading this blog post, please check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.packtpub.com/virtualization-and-cloud/mastering-aws-development-video&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Packt Website&lt;/a&gt; to view and share this video course, appreciate your support :purple_heart:!
As usually, I would like to say my favorite words after a major milestone: &lt;strong&gt;this is not an end, this is yet another starting point towards a better future!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Wayne Ye</name></author><category term="Self-Improvement" /><category term="AWS" /><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html">Course overview video Publishing information After 8 months of continuously hard working, this &amp;lt;Master AWS Development&amp;gt; video course is now live at: Packt Website, I described this course as below: Amazon Web Services (AWS) is the gold standard of the cloud. If you are web and cloud computing developer, your life becomes much easier by diving deeper into AWS. This course shows you how to use AWS services such as IAM, S3, EC2, and RDS/Dynamo to make your applications reliable and have a consistent performance. You’ll build modern serverless applications on the cloud, and use native computing solutions such as Lambda ECS/Fargate to implement cutting-edge container technology. Finally, learn a few popular AWS services like SQS, Cognito, and Kinesis. By the end of this course, you’ll be a master at building, deploying, and managing your applications on AWS. And you’ll know how to scale and secure your applications thanks to industry best practices.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Passing AWS Certified Solutions Architect</title><link href="https://wayneye.me/self-improvement/passing-aws-certified-solutions-architect/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Passing AWS Certified Solutions Architect" /><published>2017-06-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-06-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://wayneye.me/self-improvement/passing-aws-certified-solutions-architect</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wayneye.me/self-improvement/passing-aws-certified-solutions-architect/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.ibb.co/jsUja5/AWS_CSA_Associate.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 years of AWS hands on experience, two months of preparation, 30 hours of course learning, 300+ exam practices, this was the work I’ve done to pass the &lt;strong&gt;AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate&lt;/strong&gt;, my exam result is below:
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Overall Score: 81%&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Topic Level Scoring:&lt;br /&gt;
1.0 Designing highly available, cost efficient, fault tolerant, scalable systems: 81%&lt;br /&gt;
2.0 Implementation/Deployment: 83%&lt;br /&gt;
3.0 Security: 72%&lt;br /&gt;
4.0 Troubleshooting: 100%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frankly speaking, it was below my own expectation (&amp;gt; 90%), I wish I can do better two years later ^_^.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My tips and experience are summarized below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Solid&lt;/em&gt; understanding on these fundamental pillar services: IAM, EC2, S3, RDS and VPC, I feel these covered more than 60% of the quiz (just a rough number IMHO, correct me if i am wrong).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good overall understanding on CloudTrail, CloudWatch, Route53, SQS, SWF, Storage Gateway, CloudFront, doing practice exam and reading their FAQs would be sufficient.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;#1 + #2 above should’ve secure 80%+, spend 80% of your exam preparation on them should be a right strategy to pass the final exam. However, please do not assume you can smash every single question which belongs to #1+#2, questions &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be really tricky (even Ryan couldn’t make it 100% ^_^)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For some numbers/limits that may come up in the exam, but they are not easy to remember and very easy to got messed up, you can list them on a small paper, read them 5 minutes before getting into the final exam, I posted mine below FYI:) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note:  I wouldn’t bother referring any detailed knowledge points for #1/#2 above or other services like Kinesis, SNS, Server Migration service, etc because Ryan had done an outstanding job in his course, thank you, Ryan! Hat off to you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shared my learning notes and small paper for “last-5-minutes quick catching” before starting, hope it can help you a little bit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complete learning notes&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.evernote.com/l/AAGRf3_SHGdA068R-d-YzKpsmHAodYtV-kk&quot;&gt;https://www.evernote.com/l/&lt;wbr /&gt;AAGRf3_SHGdA068R-d-&lt;wbr /&gt;YzKpsmHAodYtV-kk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;last-5-minutes small paper&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.evernote.com/l/AAEEv-F5bLhEgpL9Chi90FDu3XLnVSmCpZU&quot;&gt;https://www.evernote.&lt;wbr /&gt;com/l/AAEEv-&lt;wbr /&gt;F5bLhEgpL9Chi90FDu3XLnVSmCpZU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Wayne Ye</name></author><category term="Self-Improvement" /><category term="AWS" /><category term="Technology" /><summary type="html">3 years of AWS hands on experience, two months of preparation, 30 hours of course learning, 300+ exam practices, this was the work I’ve done to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate, my exam result is below:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Storage+Media home server for less than $300</title><link href="https://wayneye.me/geek/Storage-Media-Home-Server-Less-Than-300/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Storage+Media home server for less than $300" /><published>2017-03-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-03-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://wayneye.me/geek/Storage-Media-Home-Server-Less-Than-300</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wayneye.me/geek/Storage-Media-Home-Server-Less-Than-300/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been researched and watched many NAS options to setup a home storage+media server during the past year, and so far there was no perfect answer, either lacking features/performance, or way too expensive… An Intel Celeron CPU + 1GB mem with a customized Linux (in other words: closed source )running Plex or something else, and the cost is like $400 (terrible hardware performance), or $800+/$1000+, way too expensive, examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Synology-DS216J-NAS-DiskStation-DS216j/dp/B01BNPT1EG/ref=sr_1_4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1490657211&amp;amp;sr=8-4&amp;amp;keywords=network+attached+storage&quot;&gt;Synology DS216J NAS DiskStation (DS216j)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/EX4100-Diskless-Network-Attached-Storage/dp/B00TB8XMR0/ref=sr_1_13?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1490657211&amp;amp;sr=8-13&amp;amp;keywords=network+attached+storage&quot;&gt;WD My Cloud EX4100 Diskless Expert Series 4-Bay NAS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/NETGEAR-ReadyNAS-Performance-Attached-RN524X00-100NES/dp/B01M7X2FP2/ref=sr_1_2?s=electronics&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1490657698&amp;amp;sr=1-2&amp;amp;keywords=network+attached+storage+DS916&quot;&gt;NETGEAR ReadyNAS 524X High Performance 10GbE 4-bay Network Attached Storage Diskless&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t miss awesome &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freenas.org/&quot;&gt;Free NAS&lt;/a&gt;, but the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/FreeNAS-Mini-Network-Attached-Diskless/dp/B00EQJ1BTU/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1490657211&amp;amp;sr=8-2-spons&amp;amp;keywords=network+attached+storage&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;hardware&lt;/a&gt; to run it costs $999, OMG…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-2xx-solution&quot;&gt;The $2XX solution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought this just right Dell Poweredge T20 for $267, it has an Intel Pentium G3220 3.0GHz CPU, 4GB memory and 1TB hard drive, much more powerful than 90% NAS machines, and with 1TB drive built-in, which saves approximate another $50, i installed Ubuntu 14.04 LTS on it, so that it has tons of customizing ways and I can do all sorts of crazy things on it :) By installing the awesome &lt;a href=&quot;https://emby.media/&quot;&gt;Emby Media Server&lt;/a&gt;, my home thearter finished with last piece, all my movies/videos/photos got stored inside it, I configured it to be auto wake/sleep by adding the following line into crontab:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;0 22 * * * rtcwake -m disk -s 39600&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images10.newegg.com/productimage/59-155-115-04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dell Poweredge T20&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Wayne Ye</name></author><category term="Geek" /><category term="Geek" /><category term="Hack" /><summary type="html">Background I have been researched and watched many NAS options to setup a home storage+media server during the past year, and so far there was no perfect answer, either lacking features/performance, or way too expensive… An Intel Celeron CPU + 1GB mem with a customized Linux (in other words: closed source )running Plex or something else, and the cost is like $400 (terrible hardware performance), or $800+/$1000+, way too expensive, examples: Synology DS216J NAS DiskStation (DS216j) WD My Cloud EX4100 Diskless Expert Series 4-Bay NAS NETGEAR ReadyNAS 524X High Performance 10GbE 4-bay Network Attached Storage Diskless I didn’t miss awesome Free NAS, but the hardware to run it costs $999, OMG… The $2XX solution I bought this just right Dell Poweredge T20 for $267, it has an Intel Pentium G3220 3.0GHz CPU, 4GB memory and 1TB hard drive, much more powerful than 90% NAS machines, and with 1TB drive built-in, which saves approximate another $50, i installed Ubuntu 14.04 LTS on it, so that it has tons of customizing ways and I can do all sorts of crazy things on it :) By installing the awesome Emby Media Server, my home thearter finished with last piece, all my movies/videos/photos got stored inside it, I configured it to be auto wake/sleep by adding the following line into crontab: 0 22 * * * rtcwake -m disk -s 39600</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">FC Barcelona Miracle Comeback!</title><link href="https://wayneye.me/FC-Barcelona-Miracle-Comeback" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FC Barcelona Miracle Comeback!" /><published>2017-03-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-03-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://wayneye.me/FC-Barcelona-Miracle-Comeback</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wayneye.me/FC-Barcelona-Miracle-Comeback">&lt;h2 id=&quot;04到61---史诗般的逆转&quot;&gt;0:4到6:1 - 史诗般的逆转&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-04-to-61---epic-comeback&quot;&gt;From 0:4 to 6:1 - Epic comeback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2017年3月8日，巴塞罗那诺坎普球场，加泰罗尼亚足球巨人巴塞罗那队坐镇主场迎战巴黎圣日耳曼队，带着首回合0:4的比分，开始了几乎所有人都认为的荣誉之战，绝大多数人（包括我在内），都认为巴萨可能会赢，但绝不可能翻盘，自有欧洲冠军杯以来，没有任何球队在落后4球的情况下能搬回来，迄今为止最惊天动地的翻盘出现在13年前，AC米兰主场4:1战胜拉科鲁尼亚，回到拉科主场，由马凯，潘迪亚尼、贝莱隆等人领衔实现4:0的疯狂逆转。此次虽说巴萨有世上无双的MSN三叉戟，巴黎账面上也绝对比当年的AC米兰差了点点，但是毕竟巴萨可是可怜得连个客场进球都没有，而大巴黎状态正佳，进1球就几乎可以宣告巴萨死刑，因为在此情况下他们需要进6球，面对由当世顶尖中卫蒂亚戈席尔瓦领衔的大巴黎防线，这种期望值是否太。。。然而，足球就是足球，理性分析与实际结果的差距经常巨大！就在此时，就在此地，巴塞罗那队实现了欧冠历史上绝无仅有的超级大逆转，全世界所有足球迷，即使不是巴萨的粉丝，都被此神迹彻底燃爆！&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mar 8th 2017, Camp Nou stadium at Barcelona, the Catalan giant faced Paris Saint Germain, with a 0:4 loss taken from 1st leg, started a “honor bound” from majority people’s point of view, most people (including me), would guess Barca can win, but they won’t be able to comeback, from the very beginning history of European Champions League, there was no even one club could comeback after 4 goals behind, so far the greatest comeback was 13 years ago, at the first leg AC Milan beat Deportivo de La Coruña at 4:1, then AC Milan was crushed by 4:0 with the crazy performance from Makaay, Pandiani and Valeron. Although Barca has unequaled MSN trident, and the squad of PSG might be slightly weaker than AC Milan, but after all Barca even doesn’t have an away goal, PSG is so in form, and even if they score just 1 goal and sentence Barca to death, because Barca has to score 6 at this situation, facing the PSG defense line led by one of the best CBs in the world: Thiago SIlva, the expectation would be….. However, football is futball, the difference between rational analytics and actual result is always huge! Right here, right now, Barcelona achieved the greatest comeback in the entire UCL history, all the football funs in the world, even not Barca funs, were all very excited by this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://n0bycw-dm2306.files.1drv.com/y3m1Cf4die44v2SZBPs1PQJtHwLJE62tF-jhQoZwA-Wyvg31OSmMrQp3NYVi2lkr16tFUsDvjqJ-xLWAxB2z0czr7EP5XzmE-Iw_0iKypRfLJwvblMRLLgF51Bu76jP0337qw78uCBUv9aDfgI5Htqv2CFO-Is3c3L4MSl5irHNhHg/17190536_10154486175715885_4088018240925086714_n.jpg?psid=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://oebycw-dm2306.files.1drv.com/y3mVJVpH6XYGXxWaokJIcD6IjF8s5dWWXuhgqbKS4B9Uc7Z9FVyCVYsiSK-RjrShplF47afM0o5yIoRbuZKmmVSPnFXKdRCBOGeQUT0yeMUIgMrf5DaJidHLbTCDAt0XsRZH51WvqqgB1MGtSGnoOnK3qTISr2sTCjLIwgP0gWjLUc/17098719_10154486190285885_7784151707603959815_n.jpg?psid=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nebycw-dm2306.files.1drv.com/y3mR4d8fxx5f0uesjkcrrlY89xcVjh-gyO3AAr-cDtHj_B_j-E-Q9GJfzg5ic_O7t7POIamxgvAP60N5ohbU5dorGJJ8WyWUkDykF80WQh6nffng6hQICJRoN-adWH78DY6i7T0Tt6PMPsTJMyMWKARUvRc2BfmRnhyGJ5lkDNBIgY/17190846_10154486188160885_1108782006892523299_n.jpg?psid=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lkbycw-dm2306.files.1drv.com/y3mz1Ea_w98OIMJf8wIZiGf3Q6Cd8Jwyk6UBnFi3KODu0TZ0tMQgnYCaBTpGL0gapfvqVL5GF4mAMlMMWOBPOVJuTtALnXun1FrbUmwaAg4dGNLGdSBNdnW3vAiVbEv6VfsXussZxX4-sdlmJuAljJ5N2GrwXX8WzFpm1ZImaWHik4/gettyimages-649682672.jpg?psid=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lubycw-dm2306.files.1drv.com/y3mhTLF9Lct7BDQoNqgHagmiww5oQ62v0npqcaF7UUwT4cUxyGIwN0wMe8o0Z0kfMvXY4YxBBe_lmjFavwfTlaSvbTr3MZocr-SJa4Y0yoQYwHjg_qIXvXZLDfCEa3gEWSGyfThGiWxlbjhQmpj_AZE30gqADLLUsnQQCdTgJ5ZAB0/skysports-psg-barcelona-barca-luis-suarez-champions-league-victory-celeb_3905948.jpg?psid=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mkbycw-dm2306.files.1drv.com/y3mSGRvjAv6_dqQW_hjNV_BgNZhKtpkY4boGIV5jgebZH5l1dR17YFnlmmDbggZSWWmJQf2zYIYYYzbtHHEcmKggSgLJXoROHHQiAjkir2C97ZMGXSzr83bcn3O3TVbmsNd5LMBFa_LyCCiUFz4TX6T3TiAHcV2Um6q_SlBXKov60I/17190545_10154486184565885_632884942784472297_n.jpg?psid=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mubycw-dm2306.files.1drv.com/y3mXxRpfrhwrnreHqaylQLSyuIQnKsc5LY9AvW5TU8F-I8riV1mWu71r4WNmDrnBA0HNKEa1jjCTR3mQWMRLoaB3W9BRonnFEej8-g3YfnPPkxbPftaFui5rNnPaG9lqvtxbEs2Ph7Otnx60tEzpaHsPNxlK0myGvgNmCMu8QsRB4U/17191039_10154486193445885_2898191572842903328_n.jpg?psid=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;本球痴从里瓦尔多时代就是巴萨的铁杆粉丝，昨天赛前开始看新闻，恩里克说巴黎进我们4个，我们可以进6个（我心里想他真敢说。。。），在网上看这场球时，从开场觉得有1%的希望，到半场结束觉得有10%的希望，然后下半场从卡瓦尼进球到80分钟时我觉得几乎没戏了，但巴萨将士们没有放弃！以内少为首的小伙子们没有再考虑任何的战术打法，也许他们只有一个信念：“对得起全场买票看球的10万明球迷和全球的粉丝们”，发起最后的反击号角，不到最后一刻绝不放弃！10分钟内连进三球！！！最后5分钟门将特尔施特根全在对方半场和禁区，此战彻底燃爆了所有球迷，无论用什么赞扬的辞藻送给巴萨队员和教练都不为过！&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;有些人简单地批评巴黎太保守，他们忽视了老马哥和小野兽乌姆蒂蒂是多么变态，布教授老白也是巅峰状态，梅老板也是从一而终的大将风度，苏神则全场跟大巴黎后卫死磕，鬼魅的跑位赢得一个进球和一个点球，最值得大书特书的是内少：全场无数次被踢倒爬起，不抱怨，不打嘴炮，始终目光坚毅，发起一波又一波冲击，当之无愧全场最佳，最后10分钟（从85到95），内马尔以一己之力将只剩一只手扒在悬崖边的加泰罗尼亚巨人神奇般的拉回！展现了平时不长为人所知的顽强与坚韧，一战封神！绝对的未来巴萨领袖！&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;权威网站whoscored赛后数据统计和评分截图如下，巴萨这边，内少10分满分，全场最佳当值无愧！反观PSG，触球最多的球员居然是门将Trapp：50次，实在可怜&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dmcj3a-dm2306.files.1drv.com/y3mQV709k__VJ_TFR7ENmSp5xnnfvOHXbzihHSCe1KY57r8xVo2RG0WSUNRdeypu1lZI6FXldBUpESpWCXoGvj7iMCtCdi8iu4VR2oN_1SRmLF-boJCgL31zG9_FnTMKRB7GYGNGeNgGbtnLK8pgNLiDjAbvFk8HoPDF-HaDQUZ-II/barca-rating.png?psid=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cwcj3a-dm2306.files.1drv.com/y3m-DKYrqHcilnJYO3eAdDYhbTdFUNdHgcNXb_1ykDtSSiNUI9zN0yu_fslXYStXJUSa-MvLmLOjx4KWB_Q9FBN3AELjkZbiNqqnaWzswY75kb9Z5PJuxs7QrqeUMtJwQ_PHHpic9azEupVp9dSeJGOIHmgPhwrSqefbOhqPUWG43A/psg-rating.png?psid=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nubycw-dm2306.files.1drv.com/y3mInaUHB053FluiqvVAAica_ve0F1sznZou9g9FDhUBmDgMa72chdsLLDMIdjwcOAFmVlQZeiCx6MCa45EavcFE_n8F3KYunGdF8KTVcbr-kn05OUz9i9sGb-OYXA2oCMdJ_voXCJ7s_nrkGiqvcZJPzz0ijoFbOk40aovRsITyNQ/17103238_10154485165180885_5623622492119778186_n.jpg?psid=1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Força Barça! More than a Club&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Wayne Ye</name></author><category term="Life" /><category term="Life" /><summary type="html">0:4到6:1 - 史诗般的逆转 From 0:4 to 6:1 - Epic comeback 2017年3月8日，巴塞罗那诺坎普球场，加泰罗尼亚足球巨人巴塞罗那队坐镇主场迎战巴黎圣日耳曼队，带着首回合0:4的比分，开始了几乎所有人都认为的荣誉之战，绝大多数人（包括我在内），都认为巴萨可能会赢，但绝不可能翻盘，自有欧洲冠军杯以来，没有任何球队在落后4球的情况下能搬回来，迄今为止最惊天动地的翻盘出现在13年前，AC米兰主场4:1战胜拉科鲁尼亚，回到拉科主场，由马凯，潘迪亚尼、贝莱隆等人领衔实现4:0的疯狂逆转。此次虽说巴萨有世上无双的MSN三叉戟，巴黎账面上也绝对比当年的AC米兰差了点点，但是毕竟巴萨可是可怜得连个客场进球都没有，而大巴黎状态正佳，进1球就几乎可以宣告巴萨死刑，因为在此情况下他们需要进6球，面对由当世顶尖中卫蒂亚戈席尔瓦领衔的大巴黎防线，这种期望值是否太。。。然而，足球就是足球，理性分析与实际结果的差距经常巨大！就在此时，就在此地，巴塞罗那队实现了欧冠历史上绝无仅有的超级大逆转，全世界所有足球迷，即使不是巴萨的粉丝，都被此神迹彻底燃爆！ Mar 8th 2017, Camp Nou stadium at Barcelona, the Catalan giant faced Paris Saint Germain, with a 0:4 loss taken from 1st leg, started a “honor bound” from majority people’s point of view, most people (including me), would guess Barca can win, but they won’t be able to comeback, from the very beginning history of European Champions League, there was no even one club could comeback after 4 goals behind, so far the greatest comeback was 13 years ago, at the first leg AC Milan beat Deportivo de La Coruña at 4:1, then AC Milan was crushed by 4:0 with the crazy performance from Makaay, Pandiani and Valeron. Although Barca has unequaled MSN trident, and the squad of PSG might be slightly weaker than AC Milan, but after all Barca even doesn’t have an away goal, PSG is so in form, and even if they score just 1 goal and sentence Barca to death, because Barca has to score 6 at this situation, facing the PSG defense line led by one of the best CBs in the world: Thiago SIlva, the expectation would be….. However, football is futball, the difference between rational analytics and actual result is always huge! Right here, right now, Barcelona achieved the greatest comeback in the entire UCL history, all the football funs in the world, even not Barca funs, were all very excited by this! 本球痴从里瓦尔多时代就是巴萨的铁杆粉丝，昨天赛前开始看新闻，恩里克说巴黎进我们4个，我们可以进6个（我心里想他真敢说。。。），在网上看这场球时，从开场觉得有1%的希望，到半场结束觉得有10%的希望，然后下半场从卡瓦尼进球到80分钟时我觉得几乎没戏了，但巴萨将士们没有放弃！以内少为首的小伙子们没有再考虑任何的战术打法，也许他们只有一个信念：“对得起全场买票看球的10万明球迷和全球的粉丝们”，发起最后的反击号角，不到最后一刻绝不放弃！10分钟内连进三球！！！最后5分钟门将特尔施特根全在对方半场和禁区，此战彻底燃爆了所有球迷，无论用什么赞扬的辞藻送给巴萨队员和教练都不为过！ 有些人简单地批评巴黎太保守，他们忽视了老马哥和小野兽乌姆蒂蒂是多么变态，布教授老白也是巅峰状态，梅老板也是从一而终的大将风度，苏神则全场跟大巴黎后卫死磕，鬼魅的跑位赢得一个进球和一个点球，最值得大书特书的是内少：全场无数次被踢倒爬起，不抱怨，不打嘴炮，始终目光坚毅，发起一波又一波冲击，当之无愧全场最佳，最后10分钟（从85到95），内马尔以一己之力将只剩一只手扒在悬崖边的加泰罗尼亚巨人神奇般的拉回！展现了平时不长为人所知的顽强与坚韧，一战封神！绝对的未来巴萨领袖！ 权威网站whoscored赛后数据统计和评分截图如下，巴萨这边，内少10分满分，全场最佳当值无愧！反观PSG，触球最多的球员居然是门将Trapp：50次，实在可怜 Força Barça! More than a Club</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Life Begins In BayArea</title><link href="https://wayneye.me/New-Life-Begins-In-BayArea" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Life Begins In BayArea" /><published>2015-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2015-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://wayneye.me/New-Life-Begins-In-BayArea</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://wayneye.me/New-Life-Begins-In-BayArea">&lt;p&gt;
    多年的梦想实现，展望崭新的人生目标!始终自勉，热诚而稳重，谦逊但专注；不卑不亢，以德服人；严于律己，宽以待人；永远斗志高昂，笑对挫折；不断修善自身，追求一颗强大的内心，永不言败！
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Long time&apos;s dream comes true, looking forward to brand new target now, self-encourage, be zealous and steady, modest but focused; be neither overbearing nor servile, win people by virtue; always be passionate, laughs in the face of setback; continuously upgrade myself, pursue a strong heart, never talking about failure!
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nkbfug-dm2306.files.1drv.com/y3m6gx0aoLm-gd5gtuiSfxqzRnmkW55QFRIVumysdFQ7TmWxHYa12D9X64Z2_hfACmcxynGNcQC1zTyEWc3rp8AgBaf2kF7Oo2mBZgHMldb4WuHYTDYV1RB7s8dKbBvu-HzP_wBHongeFY1ZV_Vt4uzUWrl5Cuw8tTHpTHn3xRczXw?width=495&amp;height=660&amp;cropmode=none&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://muabdg-dm2306.files.1drv.com/y2mVBXBNh2ReXQKgqPR9RPYaatMzF6vDn4gxPcVeVHIN2IvPvRlIE4u9jZs7Q6KGsp_E9wsCxSxRbmxzt9y65rPqn6-PPO5wat3m6IkblVwUlixzzBmsT9oIYBOfrwI6wXFXb44FIyODbc8fPwGKtRwZPJ5G39Oi9Ix4TpMzSiINpo/10920118_10152629643515885_6042541732602070749_o%201.jpg?psid=1&quot; alt=&quot;sun-rise-at-bayarea&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://neabdg-dm2306.files.1drv.com/y2mJjqRnQ_Ek2MQUW817HkyQIWka3f3__ldr3ZZHnyyAFj5_SwZAlheWMwTizPsSeHB17t8bbEDJw1zMCLkc0cd7XhdvxCshGXF2ZuEKbeB19VcG0SnIonHHJJ63Ym99XYRxZOaXGUteldd-rfL2Dlltb37EiBuSzKKTRpGetBrr08/10854875_10152629643520885_4383981454879173605_o%201.jpg?psid=1&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;img src=&quot;https://luabdg-dm2306.files.1drv.com/y2pHo4F9l5HT9Ch_puq7tIXYN0vKQVTbvbjR4iKngh4fGFQpy-wnZuX-5oTSVujLmXuJ5qtc1VRfQKqPXA8zkI7rIQfHLDsnTLHNOPTQpokMR8T14eeGlb1To3_65Fvog__5OGGtDNwum737A9BBgtmyg/10402927_10152708432740885_3179119850773801401_n.jpg?psid=1&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
   This is NOT the end of my dream, this is a brand new and important start point of pursuing new dreams!  Forza!
&lt;p/&gt;</content><author><name>Wayne Ye</name></author><category term="Life" /><category term="Life" /><summary type="html">多年的梦想实现，展望崭新的人生目标!始终自勉，热诚而稳重，谦逊但专注；不卑不亢，以德服人；严于律己，宽以待人；永远斗志高昂，笑对挫折；不断修善自身，追求一颗强大的内心，永不言败！ Long time&apos;s dream comes true, looking forward to brand new target now, self-encourage, be zealous and steady, modest but focused; be neither overbearing nor servile, win people by virtue; always be passionate, laughs in the face of setback; continuously upgrade myself, pursue a strong heart, never talking about failure! This is NOT the end of my dream, this is a brand new and important start point of pursuing new dreams! Forza!</summary></entry></feed>